很久以前
终于回家了
Home.
父亲
Father!
父亲  父亲  是我
Father! Father, it's me!
快开门  父亲
Come on, father!
你绝对不会相信我去了哪里
You are never going to believe where I've been!
爱丽丝
Alice...
一切都始于一只白色的兔子
It all began with this white rabbit,
-他想拿走我的帽子  -爱丽丝
- and he wanted to take my hat and then... - Alice?
真的是你吗
Is that really you?
不然还会是谁
Who else would I be?
你消失了很长一段时间
You were gone a very long time.
我们还以为你...
We--we thought you were--
你们以为我怎么了
You thought I was what?
死了
Dead.
白兔子  抽烟的毛虫
White rabbits, smoking caterpillars?
-巨大的蘑菇  -她以为我是傻子吗
- Giant mushrooms? - Who does she think I am, a fool?
她为什么要撒谎
Why would she lie?
你女儿得了妄想症
Your child is delusional.
她在胡思乱想  编造了这一切
She's delusional. She's making it up.
-但我能治好她  -这么说她是个骗子
- But I can cure her of this. - So she's a liar.
她就是个骗子
She a liar.
我不是骗子  这都是真的
I'm not a liar. It was real.
我会证明给他们看的
And I'm going to prove it.
境
仙
奇
缘
第一季  第一集
如今
你又把小酒店关了啊  勒罗伊
Looks like you closed down the joint again, Leroy.
你真是在抵制那位每周都得徽章的顾客啊
You're really gunning for that customer of the week plaque.
这是双赢  艾希莉
It's a win/win, Ashley.
你的墙上有我的照片
You get my mug on the wall,
我也有...
I finally get--whoa!
不好意思  哥们  我们打烊了
Sorry, brother. Closing time.
暴风雨好像就要来了
It looks like a storm's coming.
你最好找个地方躲着  免得被淋湿
You better find a place to keep dry.
我这就去
I'll get right on that.
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译  冰蓝  Alexy  Slience
翻译  茶炒栗子  某羽  潇湘月影
翻译  Mondo  进击的小虎
校对  某羽  米苏
时间轴  冰蓝  萌  兜兜兜爹
后期  吉吉
总监  wdjmhs
你在这啊
There you are.
该死
Bloody hell!
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
我路上再告诉你  我们迟到了
I'll tell you on the way. We're late.
不  我对你的重要约会不感兴趣  兔子
No, I'm not interested in your important dates, Rabbit,
对你不重要的约会也没兴趣
or your unimportant dates, for that matter.
不不不  我们不是没赶上什么事
No, no, no, no. We're not late for something.
而是没赶上一个人
We're late for someone.
谁
Who?
爱丽丝
Alice.
她需要帮助
She needs help.
你是红桃杰克
You're the Knave of Hearts.
她需要你
She needs you.
贝特莱姆精神病院
英国伦敦
请你回答问题
Answer the question, please.
爱丽丝
Alice?
我不记得了
I don't remember.
我认为你记得
Oh, I think you do.
已经过了一年了
It's been a year now,
你的陈述一直十分清晰
and you've been quite clear in your statements.
会隐形的猫
An invisible cat,
会抽水烟的毛虫
a hookah-smoking caterpillar,
能改变你的外形的食物和饮料
food and drink capable of altering your physical form,
还有凶残的红心王后
a murderous Red Queen.
而你遭遇这些事
And you encountered all these things by
全是因为掉进了一个兔子洞
literally... falling down a rabbit hole.
听上去...
Hearing it out loud, it all sounds quite...
非常荒诞  同意吗  爱丽丝
preposterous. Wouldn't you agree, Alice?
同意
Yes.
很好
Good.
再问几个问题
Just a few more questions,
也许这次我们就能放你回家了
and maybe this time, we can send you home.
你父亲最终把你带来我们这儿时
When your father finally brought you to us,
他已经束手无策了
he was at his wit's end.
让他头疼的不止是你
It wasn't just your multiple disappearances
多次消失
that had taken a toll.
还有你荒唐的解释
It was your ludicrous explanation
说你一直在为那地方
that you'd been searching for proof
搜寻证据  那个...
of this place, this...
仙境  你在那经历了
wonderland where you had
神奇  古怪而又可怕的冒险
miraculous, strange, and terrifying adventures.
你依然相信那是真的吗
Do you still believe that to be true?
喂  那是我的
Hey, that's mine.
还给我
Give it back.
有人擅闯  立定
Trespassers! Halt!
她朝迷宫方向去了
She's headed into the maze!
奉皇后之命  快停下
By order of the queen, stop!
别让她跑了
Don't let her get away!
她朝皇后的花园去了
She's headed for the queen's garden!
抓住她
After her!
我觉得她向这边跑了
I thought she went this way!
别让她跑了
She mustn't get away!
那个女孩哪去了
Where's the girl?
有人看见她吗
Has anyone seen her?
我觉得她向这边跑了
I thought she went this way!
爱丽丝
Alice?
Alice!
不
No.
那不是真的
It wasn't true.
我从没离开过英国
I never left England.
所以那都是你编出来的吗
So you just... made it all up?
为什么  为了引人注意吗
Why? For attention?
你确实如愿了  对吧
Well, you certainly got it, didn't you?
我们今天要搞清的问题是
The question we have to answer today is
什么才是真实情况
which is the real performance--
是那个讲着茶话会和残暴皇后传说的小姑娘
little girl with tales of tea parties and barbaric queens,
还是说这一切只是想象的小姐
or the young lady who says it was just her imagination?
那个小姑娘是个傻瓜
That little girl was a fool.
那承认谎言的小姐呢
And the lady?
她知道真实情况
She knows what really happened.
全面搜查
Search everywhere!
她肯定就在这里
She has to be here somewhere.
全搜过了
There's nowhere left!
别让她跑了
Don't let her get by.
她跑哪去了
Where did she go?
你在我的瓶子里干什么
What are you doing in my bottle?
告发我  我就变成巨人
Turn me in, and I get big.
此时此地  把你家夷为
Right here, right now, burst your house
喝我
千百万块闪亮的碎片
into a million shiny pieces.
咱们都不想如此  对吗
We wouldn't want that now, would we?
现在  很难再找到什么好瓶子了
Good bottles are so hard to find these days.
我叫塞勒斯
My name is Cyrus.
欢迎光临  请随意
My home is your home.
后来你重新露面时
When you finally resurfaced,
你声称去了这个仙境
you claimed to be in this... Wonderland.
能否告诉我们  你当时到底在哪里
Can you tell us where you really were?
和朋友在一起
With a friend.
在哪里
Where?
阿格拉巴听起来很美
Agrabah sounds beautiful.
我希望有朝一日得以再见
I hope one day to see it again.
你的家乡叫什么
What place do you call home?
英国
England.
但我最近觉得  那儿并不是我的家乡
Although it hasn't exactly felt like home lately.
看来  我们都是这片古怪土地上的异乡人
So we're both strangers in this most strange land.
"古怪"只是这里的特点之一
"Strange" is one word for it.
-也可以说奇妙  -还很危险
- Wondrous. - Dangerous.
我觉得你能照顾好自己
I sense that you can take care of yourself.
你很快就得回到家乡去吗
And you have to go back to your land soon?
我来到这里  确实有我的目的
Well, I do have what I came for.
什么目的
Which is what?
证明这一切都是真的
Prove that all this is real.
你想要证据  来啊  我给你证据
Oh! You want proof? Come here. I'll give you proof.
一只穿夹克和长裤还会说话的白兔
A talking white rabbit in jacket and trousers?
没人再会说这只是我的想象了
No one can say I imagined that.
是啊  毫无疑问
Yes. That much is certain.
告诉我  爱丽丝  你要证明给谁看
So tell me, Alice, who is this proof for?
你冒了这么大的风险回到这里
You've risked much to come back here.
是为了你丈夫吗
Is it... a husband?
不是  我没有丈夫
No. There's no one like that.
那就好
Good.
好什么
Good?
我的意思是  你没有和心爱的人分离
I mean, just that you're not separated from your love.
那样就太悲惨了
That'd be a terrible fate.
对  的确如此
Yes. That it would.
是为了证明给我父亲看
The proof is for my father.
他认为我疯了
He thinks I'm insane.
真的吗
Really?
你冒着生命危险
So you're risking your life for someone
就是为了一个不相信你的人
who doesn't believe in you?
真正爱上一个人时
You know... when you really love someone,
根本不需要什么证据
you don't need proof.
你能感受得到
You can feel it.
也许在你的家乡是这样
Maybe where you're from,
但在我的世界  我希望一切能
but in my land, I wish things would...
你希望一切能怎么样
You wish things would what?
爱丽丝  你找到我的瓶子了
You found my bottle, Alice.
一切皆有可能
Anything is possible.
我亲爱的小姐
Mistress mine,
你的愿望就是我的愿望
my will is thine.
说出三个愿望吧
Tell me your wishes three.
爱丽丝  如果你想要离开本院
Alice, if you wish to be released from this facility,
-你就得  -我不希望任何东西
- you need to-- - I don't wish for anything!
这和...
Would... this have
你口中遇到的那个精灵有关吧
something to do with the genie you believe you met?
你和你父亲说
You told your father that you--
你解救了他
You set him free,
你俩从一个世界到另一个世界
that the two of you traveled from world to world,
与海盗搏斗  和美人鱼共游
fighting pirates, swimming with Mermaids.
然后
And then...
男情女爱的天性使然  你们坠入了爱河
men and women being what they are, you fell in love.
你准备好承认这同样是个谎言了吗
Are you ready to admit that that was a lie as well?
越来越奇妙
Curiouser and curiouser.
我听说过沸腾之海
I've heard of the Boiling Sea,
但亲眼所见之后  觉得它比传说中更加神奇
but in person, it's even more amazing.
你也如此
As are you.
小心
Oh! Careful.
爱丽丝  我从未见过你这样的人类
I've never met a human quite like you, Alice.
我也从未见过你这样的精灵
I've never met a genie quite like you.
其实我从未见过精灵
Well, actually, I've never met a genie,
所以
So...
好了
Okay.
对不起  我还不习惯
Forgive me. I'm not used to--
我总是负责实现愿望  而不是许下愿望
I was always the one granting the wishes, not making them.
许下愿望  什么意思
Making them? What?
一百年来  我被束缚在一个瓶子里
For 100 years, I was tethered to a bottle,
被心怀鬼胎的人所奴役
a slave to the faulty dreams of man,
但自始至终  我只有一个愿望
and all that time, I only had one wish--
再也不要被囚禁
to never be a prisoner again.
而现在
And now...
我有了另一个愿望
I have another.
等等  我想
Wait. I-I think
你们人类会这时候会单膝下跪
the people in you world do this down on one--
我愿意
Yes.
什么
What?
是的  我愿意
Yes, yes, I will.
可我还有一大段话要说
No, but I had a whole speech.
又动听  又动人  而且...
It was charming and eloquent and had--
我们心心相印
Our hearts are entwined.
从现在起  只要你在附近  我就会知道
From now on, I'll know when you are near,
你也会知道
and you will know.
爱丽丝  快跑
Alice, run!
你父亲找到你的时候
When your father found you,
你已经伤心欲绝
you were inconsolable.
你说你此生的挚爱已去
You said the love of your life was gone,
被杀害了
murdered by some--
不  那
No, that's--
那不是我说的
that's not what I said.
爱丽丝  你是一个被忽略的小女孩
Alice, you were an ignored little girl
需要别人的关爱  所以你幻想出一个奇境
who wanted to be loved, so you created a fantasy land
里面全是能帮你
full of characters who'd help you become
梦想成真的人物
who you wanted to be--
高大  勇敢  迷人
tall, brave, beautiful.
你不是第一个这么做的孩子
You wouldn't be the first child to do this.
但你却是第一个长大之后
You're just the first to grow up
依然相信它是真实的姑娘
and still believe It was real.
不  我不再相信了
No. I don't believe it anymore.
我们知道你在说谎
We know you're lying.
你梦中还是会为他而哭
You still cry out for him in your sleep.
-什么  -在你梦中
- What? - In your sleep.
每晚如此
Every night, it's the same.
你为塞勒斯而哭
You cry out for Cyrus.
抱歉打扰二位了
Sorry to interrupt.
我能借他一用吗
Mind if I borrow him?
塞勒斯  不
Cyrus, no!
塞勒斯
Cyrus!
爱丽丝
Alice!
塞勒斯
Cyrus!
不
No!
塞勒斯
Cyrus.
爱丽丝
Alice?
我们有了新的疗程  可以消除你的伤痛
We have a new procedure that can take away your pain.
让你忘记
Make you forget
任何...
whatever...
你放不下的人和事
or whomever you're holding on to.
只需一次治疗
One treatment.
就都...没有了
It all just... slips away.
疼吗
Does it hurt?
有一点
A little.
但比你现在的痛苦小得多
But far less than the pain you're in right now.
在这儿签名就好
Just sign here.
好孩子
Good girl.
现在去睡会儿吧
Now go get some sleep.
明天你将展开崭新的人生
Tomorrow your life begins anew.
塞勒斯
Cyrus.
时候到了
It's time.
把那女孩带来
Fetch the girl.
至少给我点时间换衣服吧
Could you at least give me time to get dressed?
你
You.
"你"
"You"?
你就跟我说这个  "你"
That's what I get? "You"?
我也很高兴见到你  爱丽丝
Well, nice to see you, too, Alice.
你在这儿做什么
What are you doing here?
对了  快点  我们得走了
Right. Come now. We have to go.
走  不  你不是真的
Go? Oh, no. You're not real.
我无比真实
Oh, I'm very real,
而且我们现在必须走了
and we must leave now.
我已经搞定了一些警卫
I've cleared out some of the guards,
应该能出得去了
so we should be able to get out--
不  我不能走  不能走
No, I can't. I can't.
爱丽丝  听我的话
Alice, you need to listen to me.
不  我哪儿也不去
No, I'm not going anywhere.
你为什么老是这么顽固
Why must you always be so bloody stubborn?
他在这儿
There he is.
-我什么都没做  -真的
- I didn't do anything. - It's true.
我的意思是  如果她肯稍稍帮点忙
I mean, if she was the least bit helpful,
我们现在早走了
we would have been long gone by now--ow!
把他弄出去
Get him out of here.
爱丽丝  不  你认识我的
Alice, no! You know me!
你记得的
You remember.
我不想记得  我想要忘记
I don't want to remember. I want to forget.
爱丽丝  听我说
Alice, listen to me.
-不要  -他还活着
- No! - He's alive.
兔子看见他了
The Rabbit saw him.
塞勒斯  他还活着
Cyrus. He's alive.
这不可能
That's impossible.
你跟我都知道  爱丽丝
You know as well as I do, Alice.
在仙境里没有什么是不可能的
Nothing's impossible in Wonderland.
你就打算这么救我吗
Was that your idea of a rescue?
我本来就是想送个信
Well, it was supposed to be more of a message delivery type situation.
我没打算...
I wasn't planning to--
好吧  我们走吧
Right, let's go then.
你们迟到了
You're late.
真是惊喜啊
What a surprise.
对你来说  什么时候都算迟到
To you, everybody's late.
说得对  我的标准就是比较高
True. I do have high standards.
你来的这个世界不错
Nice world you got here. Oh.
这是什么玩意儿  爪子踩上去很硬
What the hell is this stuff? It's pretty hard on the paws.
爱丽丝  站住  别这么做
Alice! Stop. Don't do this.
我能帮治好你的病
I can help you get better.
我们真的要在这儿听这人废话吗
Are we really going to stand here and listen to this guy?
出现幻觉了吗  医生
Seeing things, doctor?
我听说有专门治疗幻觉的疗法呢
I hear there's a procedure for that.
我们现在怎么办
Well, what do we do now?
跑
We run.
小心
Look out!
闪开
Out of the way!
Out of my way!
不
Oh, no.
我们等着被抓吧
We'll be pinched for sure.
不  不会的
No, we won't.
-他们来了  -兔子
- They're coming. - Rabbit!
在这儿  我们就不能找个
Here? Couldn't we find somewhere
土地松软的地方  比如田野什么的
with softer ground, like a field--
快挖
Dig!
好吧
All right.
走吧
Here goes.
你在等什么
What are you waiting for?!
爱丽丝  我离开那地方的时候
Alice, I didn't exactly leave that place
闹得不是很愉快
on good terms.
我也是  但是如果赛勒斯还...
Neither did I, but if Cyrus is--
那该走的是你  不是我
Then you have to go, not me.
听着  杰克
Listen, Knave.
很久之前  我帮你找回了你的心
Once long ago, I got you back your heart.
现在  我要你帮我找回我的
Now... you need to help me get back mine.
那边
Down there!
不然你可以找那帮人试试
Or you can take your chances with them.
该死
Bloody hell.
好吧
All right, then.
下一站...仙境
Next stop... Wonderland!
人类啊
Humans.
我讨厌...
I hate...
这个该死的...
this bloody...
地方
place!
小心点  杰克
Careful, Knave.
我们在棉花糖沼里着陆了
We've landed in the mallow marsh.
当然
Of course we did,
因为一片甜点奶油形成的湖最正常不过了
because a pond made out of dessert topping makes perfect sense.
快点  动起来
Come on. Shake a leg.
两条腿都动起来
Shake two legs.
太混乱了
Ugh! What a mess.
好吧  兔子  塞勒斯在哪
Okay, Rabbit. Where's Cyrus?
告诉我们  你在哪看见他的
Tell us where you saw him.
我没亲眼见到他  你跟她说我看见他了
Well, I didn't exact see him. Did you tell her I saw him?
-你就是那么说的  -那只是比喻
- That is what you said. - It was a figure of speech.
不是  我确定不是
Nope. I'm pretty sure it wasn't.
我的意思是
Uh, what I meant was,
我在跟睡鼠喝茶
I was having tea with the Dormouse,
他说  他看见他了
and he said that he saw him.
我们千里迢迢跑过来
So we came all the way here
就因为一个总打瞌睡的老鼠所说的已经话吗
on the word of a narcoleptic rodent?
别理他  兔子  继续说
Ignore him, Rabbit. Go on.
他说塞勒斯在疯帽子的老屋子里
He said Cyrus was at the Mad Hatter's old place.
那屋子已经废弃了
It's abandoned.
疯帽子  不在仙境很久了
The Hatter--he hasn't been in Wonderland for quite some time.
他一直没回来
And he ain't never coming back.
他在我挖矿的那个世界
He's found himself a nice little life
生活得很不错呢
back in the place I was makin' mine--
要我说  那个地方...
A place, I might add...
蜻蜓就是蜻蜓
where the dragonflies aren't actually dragons.
兔子  你是长高了吗
Rabbit, are you getting taller?
很可能
Yeah, quite possibly.
这种事在这里常有得是
That kind of thing happens quite a lot around here.
我们在下沉
We're sinking.
我的脚动不了了
I can't move me feet.
兔子  那地方在哪  疯帽子的屋子在哪
Rabbit, where is it? Where's the Hatter's house?
还能在哪  拼图森林
Where else? The Tulgey Woods.
杰克  我们得出去
Knave, we need to get out of here.
-是吗  -一切都会好的
- Really? - Uh, everything's gonna be fine.
我去...我去找人帮忙
I'll just, uh... uh, uh, I'll go get help!
别担心  一切都会好起来的
Don't worry! Everything's going to work out just fine!
别动了  我们会沉得更快的
Stop moving. We'll just sink faster.
是啊  短痛不如长痛嘛
Oh, because a slow death is so much more pleasant.
太讽刺了
This is humiliating.
我就要死成一个焦糖饼干了
I'm gonna die like a bloody s'more.
什么
A what?
是一种巧克力小饼干
It's biscuits and chocolate,
再把烤过的棉花糖...
and you get toasted marsh--
别管了  重点是我们要死了
Never mind. The point is, we're gonna die.
杰克  太好了
Knave, that's brilliant.
你在做什么
What the bloody hell are you doing?
我在做糖饼干
I'm making a sore.
-是焦糖饼干  -管他什么呢
- S'mores! - Whatever.
我现在觉得把你关进精神病院是正确的
I'm starting to think you were in the nutter for a reason.
看见了吗
See?
来吧
Come on.
那只兔子呢
Where's that rabbit?
天色要晚了
It's getting late,
我今晚还想在自己的床上过夜呢
and I plan on sleepin' in me own bed tonight.
你不能走  我们还没找到塞...
You can't leave. We haven't found Cy--
塞勒斯  没错
Cyrus. Exactly.
你听见兔子说的了
You heard what the Rabbit said.
他都没看见他
He never even saw him.
如果我早知道
If I'd known that,
就不会做这些事了
I wouldn't have done any of this.
我们现在都不知道  他是不是还活着
I mean, for all we know, he isn't even alive.
如果他活着呢
What if he is?
爱丽丝...
Alice...
我离开仙境是因为我做了很多坏事
I left Wonderland because I did a lot of bad things here.
很多人想看我死
A lot of people wanna see me dead.
他们是有理由的  老实说
They have their reasons, and to be honest,
那些理由都很正当
they're good reasons.
我是为了活下去才离开这里的
I left this place for a future I'm quite keen to see,
难道你指望我  因为你的直觉就去冒险吗
and you want me to risk all that for a hunch?
我可以给你报酬
I can pay you.
什么报酬
How?
你没什么东西能给我  爱丽丝
You don't have anything to pay me, Alice.
并非如此
That's not entirely true.
我有比钱更好的东西
I have something better than money.
愿望宝石
Wishes.
我不明白
I don't get it.
为什么你不用它们把赛勒斯带回来
Why don't you just use 'em to bring Cyrus back?
愿望宝石的效果...难以预测
Wishes can be... unpredictable.
如果我用它带赛勒斯回来
If I used one to bring Cyrus back,
他回来的时候  可能会被吊在树上
he might arrive hanging from a tree
脖子上还绕着绳子
with a noose around his neck.
使用愿望宝石
See, with wishes,
往往会带有一些附带条件
sometimes there's literally a string attached.
那可得小心斟酌许什么愿了
Then one just has to be careful what they wish for.
确保它能够达到目的
Make it consequence-proof.
我能做到
Yeah, I can do that.
也就是说你会留下了来吗
So does that mean you'll stay?
我们一起找到赛勒斯  我可以许一个愿
We find Cyrus, I get a wish.
任何愿望
Anything I want.
那就带我去拼图森林
Just get me to Tulgey woods.
你真相信兔子说的话吗
So you really believe the Rabbit, then?
我知道你心存疑虑
I know you have your doubts,
但是  我相信兔子
but, yes, I believe the Rabbit.
不
Oh, no.
你在这儿  兔子
There you are, Rabbit.
我的耳朵
Oh! My ears!
介意放我下来吗
Oh! Uhh! Do you mind?
女王陛下  让我解释
Your majesty, I can explain.
你迟到了
You're late.
我知道  我知道  非常抱歉
I know. I know. I-I'm so sorry.
我已经尽可能快地赶过来了
I came as soon as I could.
你把你听到的话告诉爱丽丝了吗
So you told Alice what you heard?
是的  我告诉她赛勒斯还活着
Yes, that Cyrus was alive.
他还活着吗
Is he?
我才是问问题的人
I'll be the one asking questions.
是的  是的  那么我们扯平了吧
Right. Right. So this makes us all square then?
你说如果我带她回来  我可以...
You said if I got her here, I'd get--
我说的是游戏结束以后咱俩再算总账
I said we'd settle up when the game was complete.
现在一切都才刚刚开始
We are still setting up the board.
至于你的朋友爱丽丝
Now as for your friend Alice,
她的一举一动你都要向我报告
I need you to report everything she does,
她去了哪儿  和谁说过话
where she goes, who she talks to,
在想些什么
what she is thinking.
我不只需要眼线
I need more than my eyes.
还需要你的耳朵
I need your ears,
你要是不帮我  亲爱的
and you will either help me, darling...
就等着来装饰这间屋子吧
or decorate this room.
明白了吗
Understood?
明白了  女...女王陛下
Yes, y-your majesty.
退下吧
Now leave.
拼图森林
The Tulgey woods.
疯帽子的家就在森林尽头
The Hatter's place is on the other side.
拼图森林  道路和居民在红心王后的慷慨庇护之下
你难道不怕这一切都是个陷阱吗
Aren't you worried this is all a trap?
只要有一丝可能  赛勒斯还活着
If there's a chance that Cyrus is alive,
我们都得去试试
We have to take it.
好吧  我们走
Right. Let's go.
红心王后  你说过就是她
The Red Queen-- you said it was also her
把赛勒斯推进了沸腾之海
who threw Cyrus into the Boiling Sea.
-她为什么要这么做  -我不知道
- Why would she do that? - I don't know,
但我很想问问她
but I'd love to ask her
看看她脸上是什么表情  让她知道
and see the look on her face when she realizes
我一点儿都不宽宏大量
I'm not the forgiving sort,
尤其是当我用这根树枝狠抽她脸的时候
particularly when said face meets this branch, repeatedly.
这可不像你
Doesn't sound like you.
医生说我对人对己都很危险
The doctors said I'm a danger to myself and to others.
你已经不相信所见的任何事了
Yeah, you can't believe everything you read now.
是的
I don't.
事实上  当我以为赛勒斯死了之后
In fact... when I thought Cyrus was dead,
我很难再相信任何事了
I stopped believing in much of anything.
怎么样了
Well?
她回来了
She's back.
那女孩正在做什么呢
And what is the girl doing now?
当然是在找她的小精灵
Looking for her genie, of course.
这不正是我们所希望的吗  贾法尔
Isn't that what we wanted, Jafar?
只有找到精灵的瓶子
What we want can't be accomplished
让得让那个女孩许下三个愿
until we have the genie's bottle
我们的目的才能达成
and the girl's made all her wishes.
要我说
So I'd say
你还没资格这样自满
perhaps you shouldn't be so pleased with yourself.
别用高人一等的语气和我说话  贾法尔
Do not talk down to me, Jafar.
我可是王后
I'm the Queen.
都是权力在作祟
That's the thing about power.
可是权力  是那么转瞬即逝
Hmm. It can be so fleeting.
你这是在威胁我吗
Is that a threat?
不是
No.
威胁是给那些措手不及的人准备的
Threats are for people who aren't prepared to act.
等等
Wait.
你需要我
You need me.
已经不需要了
Not anymore.
我能做到你做不成的事
But I did what you could not. I--
我让爱丽丝重回仙境了
I brought Alice back to Wonderland.
你确实管用过
Which means your work
但现在你已经没有利用价值了
and your usefulness to me is done.
下面的事就交给我吧
I'll take it from here.
你知道...
Do you know...
她在哪儿吗
where she is?
你知道吗
Do you?
没错
That's right.
你不知道
You don't.
现在你可不是在阿格拉巴了  亲爱的
Now you're not in Agrabah anymore, darling.
这是我的王国
This is my world,
只有我才知道她在哪儿
which means only I know exactly where she is.
只有我才知道她要去哪儿
Only I know exactly where she's going.
如果你仍想让我帮你
So if you want my help,
那好  交易继续
yes... our deal remains.
我会帮你得到愿望宝石的
I will get you those wishes.
拿什么作交换呢
In return for what, exactly?
到时候再说
All in due time.
你怎么还不踏上你那破毯子
So why don't you get on that raggedy carpet of yours
滚蛋呢
and fly away?
我来管爱丽丝就行了
And let me take care of Alice.
如你所愿
For your sake...
祝你成功
I hope you do.
我们一直在走
We've been walking forever.
应该到疯帽子家了
We should be at the Hatter's house by now.
该死
Oh, bloody hell.
通缉  死活不限
红心骑士
我走之后  你都干了什么
What exactly did you do after I left?
别问了
Don't ask.
该往哪儿走了
Now which way?
向上
Up.
我不想再四处乱逛了
I'm tired of wandering around.
我们得换个视角
We need a different point of view.
什么意思
What do you mean?
爬得够高  我就能看到疯帽子的家了
If I get high enough, I can see the Hatter's house.
我受够了
Enough of these.
我看到疯帽子的家了  离这儿很近了
I can see it! The Hatter's place--it's not that far!
杰克
Knave?
威尔
Will?
柴郡猫
Cheshire.
是你啊  你吓到我了
It's you. You gave me a fright.
小柴
Chesh?
你不记得我了吗
You remember me, right?
我是爱丽丝
It's Alice.
是啊  我记得你
Yes, I remember.
你看起来...变了好多
You look... different.
万物都在变化  不是吗
Everything does, doesn't it?
仙境到处是陌生人
Wonderland has grown stranger.
我是  你也是
I'm stranger. You're stranger.
我们都是陌生人
Together we are... strangers.
好吧  你还好吗
Well, then... how do you do?
既然我们又是朋友了
Now that we're friends again,
你不会想吃朋友的
you wouldn't want to eat a friend now...
是吧
Would you?
没加胡椒的话当然不吃
Mmm, certainly not without pepper.
这几天我食不果腹
The pickings are slimmer these days.
这片森林曾经物产丰饶
These woods used to be full of food,
如今  这儿唯一的食物...
but now the only thing it's full of...
就是你
is you.
红心王后向我保证
The red queen promised
你的味道绝对鲜美可口
you would be the sweetest meat I've ever tasted.
那就试试吧
Let's see, shall we?
现在
Now then...
去找跟你体型相当的猎物吧
Go pick on somebody your own size.
真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
你  你竟...
You. You were--
如此英勇
Brave?
如此勇敢
Daring?
偷走我的愿望宝石
Stealing my wishes.
那个啊
Oh, that.
那只是个误会
I think maybe you misunderstand.
我是想保护它们啊
I was just protecting the wishes.
你觉得我会信吗
You expect me to believe that?
不会  不
Not really, no.
可问题是  我又回来
But can we focus on the part where I came back
救了你啊
and saved your life?
你知道愿望是没法被偷走的
You know you can't steal a wish.
它必须被赐予
It has to be granted.
我当然知道
Of course I did.
人尽皆知
Everybody knows that.
我们去找塞勒斯吧
Let's go get Cyrus.
杰克
Knave.
在那边  快
Over there! Hurry!
塞勒斯
Cyrus?!
疯帽子的房子
The Hatter's house.
塞勒斯
Cyrus.
Cyrus!
塞勒斯
Cyrus.
我在这
I'm here.
爱丽丝
Alice.
他一定在这里  太黑了看不见
He must be here. It's too dark to tell,
也许他在睡觉
or maybe he's sleeping or something.
你们在这啊
Oh, here you are.
我一直在找你们
I've been looking all over.
我带了一整支队伍
I showed up with a whole troop
去把你们拖出沼泽
to pull you out of that marsh,
但是你们走了
but you were gone.
没关系  兔子  挖洞送我们回家吧
It's okay, Rabbit. Just dig us back home.
塞勒斯不在这里
Cyrus ain't here.
不  他一定在
No, he must be here.
爱丽丝
Alice...
Alice.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
但他不在这里
But he's not here.
据我所知  他从没来过
And as far as I can tell, he never was.
也许
Maybe...
也许睡鼠说错了房子  或者
maybe the Dormouse just named the wrong house, or--
兔子  够了
Rabbit, enough.
如果塞勒斯来了
If Cyrus were here,
那他早该出现了
wouldn't he have shown himself by now?
所以他真的走了
So he really is gone.
爱丽丝
Alice.
你又一次让她痛失所爱
You made her lose Cyrus twice.
为什么要这样做
Why would you do that?
威尔  兔子  快过来
Will, Rabbit, come quickly!
我找到了这个  这是塞勒斯的
I found this. It was Cyrus's.
你从哪找到的
Where did you get that?
就在草地里
It was just here in the grass.
他还活着
He's alive.
任何东西都无法在沸腾之海中存活
Nothing could survive the Boiling Sea.
如果它完好无损  那他也活着
If it survived, so did he.
爱丽丝  那条项链是带有魔法的
Alice, that necklace-- it's magic.
所以它才没被损坏  戴项链的人
That's why it survived. The guy wearing it--
他不过是血肉之躯
he was just flesh and blood.
他走了
He's gone.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
现在我们走吧
Now let's get out of here.
兔子可以挖洞
The Rabbit can dig his hole.
你可以过上新的生活  拥有新的爱情
You can make a new life, meet somebody else.
-不  -不
- No. - No?
我不走
I'm not going.
爱丽丝  这不是固执的时候
Alice, this isn't the time to be stubborn.
我没有固执
I'm not being stubborn.
你就有
Yes, you are.
如果你想走  就走吧
If you want to leave, leave.
但我要留下来
But I'm staying.
就因为那条项链吗
Because of a necklace?
因为他在这里
Because he's here.
但你没有证据
But you have no proof.
真正爱上一个人时
When you really love someone,
根本不需要什么证据
you don't need proof.
你能感受得到
You can feel it.
他在这里
He's here.
我要找到他
I'm gonna find him.
唯一的问题是
Only question is...
你会和我一起吗
are you coming with me?
我就怕你会这么问我
I was afraid you were going to ask me that.
这是同意了吗
Is that a "yes"?
该死的
Bloody hell.
走吧
Come on then.
爱丽丝
Alice.
不
No!